<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Announcements on Master of Software Engineering</title><link>/categories/Announcements/</link><description>Recent content in Announcements on Master of Software Engineering</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/Announcements/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introducing Sound Realms: Mace &amp; Magic</title><link>/sound-realms/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sound-realms/</guid><description>Sound Realms: Mace &amp;amp; Magic is an audio-based solo RPG adventure app for iOS and Android devices. I have been programming on it for around 8 hours per week since October 2020, so by now it is starting to shape up real good! Download the free demo adventure to your phone if you are intrigued.
The idea is to craft an inspiring and captivating experience that lets you use your imagination.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Frontman</title><link>/Introducing-Frontman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 10:58:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>/Introducing-Frontman/</guid><description>Frontman is a very light-weight NGINX reverse proxy that is deployed using Docker. Its purpose is to act as the entry point to your server. It will redirect incoming traffic to one out of many Docker-based applications running on the same server, based on the hostname in the incoming request.
The rationale behind this is that it enables you to host as many services as you want on the same server, while still only keeping ports 80 and 443 open to the outside world.</description></item><item><title>Welcome!</title><link>/welcome/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 17:27:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>/welcome/</guid><description>Welcome to my blog on software engineering!
In my daily work as a software engineer, I read and think a lot on various topics and also write a lot of notes as I do so. My main goal with this website is to gather some of my notes in a single place and in a slightly more readable format. By making everything public it feels like I force myself into cultivating my thoughts and ideas into a more concrete form.</description></item></channel></rss>